<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="000style.xsl"?>
<teiCorpus>
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digitised and Encoded copy of Negro Slavery by Zachary MacAulay</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Transcribed from digital copy available from Recovered Histories at
                    http://www.recoveredhistories.org/pamphlet1.php?page=1&amp;orderby=MaxID&amp;catid=66</authority>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Negro Slavery; or, A View of Some of the More Prominent Features of
                            that State of Society, as it Exists in the United States of America and
                            in the Colonies of the West Indies, Especially in Jamaica</title>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Printed for Hatchard and Son, Piccadilly, and J. and A. Arch,
                            Cornhill</publisher>
                        <distributor>Sold Also by W. Graphel, Church street, and G. and J. Robison,
                            Castle Street, Liverpool.</distributor>
                        <date when="1823">1823</date>
                        <pubPlace>
                            <settlement>London</settlement>
                        </pubPlace>
                    </publicationStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <TEI>
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title/>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Transcribed by a student of Digital History at Sheffield Hallam
                        University</authority>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <bibl>
                        <biblScope>54</biblScope>
                    </bibl>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body> <p>such fools as consent to be confined to one man: their engagements, therefore, are merely temporary, and are not considered as at all binding. Mr. Cooper never heard of any attempt, by agreement between masters, to bring together on the same plantation a man and white who lived on different plantations. Nor could it in general be of any very great use to do so, while there is no such thing among them as a marriage-tie.</p>
			<p>It is, doubtless, in part owning to this cause, and to the universal profligacy of manners prevailing among Blacks and Whites, that the <interp>Negroes, in <placename key="Jamaica" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?params=18___N_77___w"> </place>, are a very unprolific race : not that they are so naturally, - but they are made so by the brutalizing and demoralizing system of government under which they live, which is notoriously most unfriendly to the production of life, and, in several ways, tends directly to its destruction. Among other things, it causes the women to be extremely careless of themselves when breeding, so that miscarriages are very common ; and it produces also the most miserable neglect of their children. key="I believe that this is true because if women don't take care of themselves the body cannot physically and mentally take care of another." n=" Slave masters even beat pregnant women, devising ways to do it without harming the baby. Slave masters would dig a hole big enough for the woman's stomach to lay in and proceed with the lashings." cert="high" ref=" http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treatment_of_slaves_in_the_United_States"> </interp> </p>
			<p>The Negros on <placename key="Georgia" ref=" https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?params=32.9605___N_83.1132___w"> </place>Georgia estate do not keep up their numbers. There were in one year only seven births, through the while population is about four hundred. Mr. Cooper attributes this non-increase to their morally degraded condition ; to prostitution and its various con-sequences, including disease ; to hard work, and to severity of punishment. Indeed, he considers that having no other motive to exertion in their present state, they would not work at all, were it not that neglect would be visited with severe punishment. </p>
			<p>In <placename key="Jamaica" ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?params=18___N_77___w" </place> the slaves are scarcely ever taught to read. </p>
			<p>In every parish there is a rector, who, generally speaking, preaches, every Sunday morning at the parish church ; and  a curate, who has a chapel. The service however, takes place at the very time which may be</p>

                
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
</teiCorpus>